<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matheus Barbieri</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Matheus Barbieri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Matheus de Souza Barbieri</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:39:45 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automate Delivery specification with ArgoCD ApplicationSet</title><link>/posts/argo-application-set/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:39:45 -0300</pubDate><guid>/posts/argo-application-set/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m without motivation enough to write a post talking about how a delivery pipeline should be, how to relate real-state x desired-state or why you should use this or that, i particularly prefer ArgoCD by a simple resource called ApplicationSet.
ArgoCD&amp;rsquo;s ApplicationSet is a awesome feature to a delivery pipeline.
it make you specify in a manifest how and where k8s manifests should be applied the argocd read the applications sets, and create a pipeline which will apply source from parameters into destinations</description></item><item><title>Managing multi-cluster secrets with Sealed Secrets</title><link>/posts/sealled-secrets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 18:00:38 -0300</pubDate><guid>/posts/sealled-secrets/</guid><description>One of the most hard problems i have found dealing with multiple-cluster in my jobs is dealing with secrets management, create secrets for each cluster, being sure that secret works, and store them safely.
Having a proper control of this issue always be a big mess, mostly because this easily become a safety issue most of the time in companies i have passed, someone have all the secrets stored in their machine or in some dark and scared place, or all of the secrets start to be stored in one private repository where every one in a point of the time will have the access or other horrible solution like that.</description></item></channel></rss>